So, you want to learn more about Stardew Valley...
and you thought something called
"A Garbage Guide" could help you.
If so... you've come to the right place, my friend.
"Stardew Valley" was released on February 26th
and I have been searching and searching, but so far,
I haven't found a single tutorial... made by me.
First, you have to name your character.
This is a farming simulator, so what if
I just name him "Farm Simulator".
In Estonian, that's a common name.
Nah, but I'm going to keep my "Favorite Thing" a secret,
so I can reveal it as a dramatic ending.
The point of this guide is to teach you
how to become extremely rich.
So, you want to dress like this.
Some Greek philosopher once said,
"First step is to dress nice if you want to make
some serious motherfucking money."
That same guy went on to build the Coliseum.
The game's story is about some guy with
a great, stable job in the Tech industry.
Then, he has a mid-life crisis.
Sacrifices everything for a career in Agriculture.
Even though he has no experience or money.
Simple, yet beautiful...
I hate it. I'm gonna make up my own backstory.
Far into the future, in the year 1997, the computer,
"Skynet", sends a "Terminator" back in time,
to destroy the leader of the resistance, John Connor.
But then the Terminator has a mid-life crisis
and buys a farm.
So, we get to the farm, and it looks like the
house version of a meth addict.
I haven't actually played this game before.
Most people would say that completely disqualifies
me from making a guide,
and... you would be right.
The first quest is to grow a parsnip.
No-one likes parsnips. So, that's obviously a trap.
The second quest is to get to know everyone in
Pelican Town, but that didn't happen,
because I am too shy,
and no-one would approach me, because I
look like the world's biggest douche.
After a couple of days, the mayor, Lewis, will
show you the Community Center.
But why would I want to enter that death trap?
(gasp)
What's that?!
The local wizard tells you that the Community Center
is filled with "Forest Spirits",
and I can help them, and blah blah blah
Hey, Mister Wizard, if that even is your real name,
Does this look like the face of someone who gives
a flying FUCK about Forest Spirits?!
I care about MONEY, and unless these "Magical Beings"
have a disposable income, we are DONE here.
I need to do something more business-like, so I'm
going to go into this cave and fight monsters.
Ha, ha, ha! This is fun! Wait... it's SUMMER?
Wait... I've played for FIVE HOURS?!
What am I doing adventuring? Mining rare ores
will never make me real money, as opposed
to selling cabbage.
I was supposed to make more money than a
cactus seller in... in a place where cactuses
are in high demand!
I'm-I'm not very good at metaphors, okay?
But, now that I'm done having fun, it's
time to take this seriously.
So I started reading Forbes, and found out that
the hot pepper industry is booming.
Adventuring isn't completely useless, because you get
metal ores, that can be melted into bars.
Look at the metal furnaces dancing!
They are having the time of their lives.
I realize now that furnaces aren't supposed to dance...
I think I am about to start a forest fire.
If you have a copper bar, and an iron bar,
you can craft... a sprinkler.
But it was all for nothing. By the time the
peppers had finished growing...
the pepper industry was DEAD. I am
starting to give up on my dream.
I have decided to grow pumpkins. You see, the
United State-ians have this holiday in late October,
where they celebrate pumpkins and skeletons.
Yes, it sounds made up, but it is true, you can look it up.
But not only am I well versed in the world's cultures,
I am also a genius entrepreneur.
So I'm going to sell the pumpkins AFTER Halloween,
when there is no competition.
My stone walls have started to deteriorate, some have
even disappeared completely after only six months.
My Ph.D in Geology makes me think that is
not very scientific, but I wasn't sure.
So I borrowed a stone from the lab, and filmed it
over the course of six months, to see how
fast it would decompose.
But after six months... it was Earth. The game was right.
My pumpkin plan worked. I now have some money.
I also own chickens. As you can see I have two fences.
That's because I saw this documentary about some
people who wanted to make chicken pie...
Then the chickens found a wacky
way of escaping by flying away.
I think it was called "District 9".
I have built two pens for cows. I'll treat this pen better, and then tell these cows that they can become a part of these guys if they work really hard.
But, they can't. Because sure, all animals are
equal, but some are a bit... more equal..
The winter is a great time to decide how you
are going to make your fortune.
I have sold peppers and pumpkins,
and made HORSE SHIT.
Time to switch to something less... LEGAL.
Because crime does pay, kids.
So I started selling... Mayonnaise.
I didn't think I would be able to sell anything,
but Mayonnaise exploded like an atomic
bomb over our culture.
Literally everyone was doing it.
Actually, if you tasted Mayo in the late 80's to early 90's,
there was an 80% chance that it came from us.
Even with the D.E.A. destroying my base of operations, and the Colombians taking their cut, I was still making more money than I could spend in a lifetime.
I was finally rich.
Now that I am filthy rich, my first instinct was to buy an orphanage, so I can demolish it and turn it into a factory.
But there aren't any orphanages in Pelican Town,
so I bought this random house.
But no-one protested its destruction,
so what's the point?!
Now, I have to find another hobby of an
"Evil Rich Person" TV Trope.
I bought a Gold Pickaxe. Only an extremely rich person, or an idiot would buy something so useless.
Do you know how soft GOLD is?!
Just bought this new unicorn here.
It's fun to ride around here in the hills.
But, do you know what I care about a lot
more than materialistic things?
MONEY.
Huh... Joja Mart wants 4000 so they can get
the Community Center, to... demolish it and
turn it into a warehouse?!
THAT'S MY ORPHANAGE PLAN, YOU PIECE OF SHIT.
The Community Center! It's run down!
There's not even anyone living in here!
YOU ARE FUCKING TERRIBLE AT THIS.
Where the hell is the mayor?!
"I'd hate to see it all dried up."?!
WAS THAT A THREAT?!
That's it! I have had it with your anti-corporate bullshit.
I shall run for NEW MAYOR!
Turns out the game doesn't have that feature.
I was like 90 percent sure it was in the latest patch.
But that's okay, I'm going to become something bigger.
I'm going to become EMPEROR of Pelican Town.
I just do not understand, why i-why is
that not in the game?
It's like the creator has never even been to a small town.
NO. This is not his fault. This is Pelican Town's fault.
They can't handle my high energy.
I'm going to build a WALL... and make THEM pay for it.
I can't believe they built a wall and sent me an invoice...
Okay then. I shall upgrade my house so big,
it consumes the entire region!
That's it?! I can't upgrade more than that?!
But... I have so much MONEY...
and Kilian wept, for there were no more
worlds to conquer.
My failure has taught me that there might be more to
life than making money in a farming simulator.
Time to help people.
Pam, the local alcoholic, spends all her day
drinking cheap booze.
So I helped her. So she can spend all her
day drinking expensive booze.
I gave this guy the 4000, so he can build his warehouse.
It's a shitty evil plan... but it's evil enough.
The local store is getting destroyed by big
business. So I wanted to support him.
So I spent 200,000 on fertilizer.
(police sirens begin wailing in the background)
Oh... right...
Hah! F.B.I., you call that torture?
No wonder C.I.A. is considered scarier.
But after getting waterboarded, I'm pretty
pissed off that my taxes go to fund it.
No, wait... I haven't PAID any taxes...
and it was at that point I realized that I
was in some pretty deep shit.
Okay... got a problem... the government just sent
me a letter, and they say I owe them 9 million
in taxes, and a rather huge fine.
What do I do about that?
Call them, tell them that you are very sorry, and explain the situation.
Apologize? Like a seven-year old?
HOW ABOUT NO.
Pay the taxes, and the fine.
(pained mumbling)
The only solution... is to fake my own death.
So I tried that... and failed, and killed myself.
But then I woke up completely fine.
So I tried to kill myself again...
and again... and again...
Turns out... I can't die.
So I tried to leave, but the bus sent me
to this desert, not home...
and the train never stops here. YOU CAN'T LEAVE.
Wait... if you rearrange the letters in "Pelican Town",
you get "Let Panic Own".
Of course! The intro was a ruse!
You're not playing as this guy...
You're playing as THAT guy!
And this... this is HELL.
Wait... what was my favorite thing?
Oh, well that's disappointing...
and that is the Kilian Experience.
Okay, so this game was a hell of a lot more obscure when I started making this video...
but you know what it has a lot of?
It has a lot of salad, and this week's salad is m--